Nahid Shakib

Location: Greater London area

Telephone: 07462531883; Email: nahidshakib@outlook.com Right to Work: British citizen, having full right to work

Professional profile:

Motivated and Driven IT Professional

Recent graduate of an AI-driven Software Engineering bootcamp at Skills City. I am transitioning into the IT sector with a wealth of transferable skills in decision-making, problem-solving, communication, and teamwork, cultivated through my previous career experiences.

As a career changer, I am bringing a fresh perspective and a strong commitment to success in the tech industry. I developed proficiency in Python, databases, Django, React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AI, ML, cloud, OOP and Prompt Engineering. Midway through the program, I already have successfully created web pages, resolved bugs, and troubleshooted Django setup issues in collaboration with technical instructors.

My passion for technology and my enthusiasm for this career transition drive me to continuously learn and improve. I achieved outstanding grade in bootcamp, have engineering degree in other discipline, so I am confident in my ability to quickly adapt and grow, with the goal of becoming an established IT professional within the next 2 to 5 years.

I am available to start any full-time or part time remote roles with or without occasional travel to workplace.

https://myprotfolio3.vercel.app/

My Portfolio: https://github.com/NahidKakon/portfolio.git www.linkedin.com/in/nahid-shakib-0507ba86

Key IT skills:

- HTML
- CSS
- Python
- JavaScript
- DJANGO
- React

- SQL
- SQLAlchemy
- DATABASE Concepts
- DevOp
- Artificial Intelligence
- Next.js

- Machine Learning techniques
- Analytical thinking
- LLM Prompt Engineering
- Microsoft Azure Portal
- Confident PC skills
- Sanity, Firebase, Stripe

Key Transferable Skills:

- MS office (word, excel, power point, outlook)
- Drawing (used before Gerber CAD, Auto CAD, Paint 3D, Photoshop)
- Teaching and guiding
- Report writing

- Requirement analysis •
- Decision making
- Planning
- Problem solving
- Leadership
- Quick learner
- Quality assurance

- Communication skill at all levels
- Ability to see bigger picture
- User of various extranet software (eg. PLM, Lighthouse, Interlink, OneSource, CMS, FirstReact etc.)
- Working with strict Deadline

Career summary

June 2024 - Present

Al Driven Software Engineering Bootcamp - Skills City

A course which provides the building blocks and advance technical skills needed to work in Software Engineering. The program introduces various Software Engineering concepts and the opportunity to discover theory by exploring subjects online. The bootcamp also provides scope to practise and apply knowledge, completed industry project for Phoenix Software.

The course content includes:

- Gain an understanding of software fundamentals.
- Building Responsive Web Applications (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, APIs)
- Advanced topics: DevOps, AI and Machine Learning Techniques
- Working in a team with established industry clients to work on a specified project brief to solve a real issue.

- Advanced Python and Automation.
- Microsoft Azure fundamentals.
- Creating a Portfolio website with React.
- Using SQL to manipulate databases in real-time.
- Teamwork, wellbeing, and career progression.

November 2021 to June 2024 Company: March 29 UK Ltd., Huddersfield, UK Job: Technologist- Fabric, Chemical Compliance &	Responsibilities: Checking test reports, certificates and other documents, uploading and submitting them into customers' extranets.
Sustainability	Communicating with customers, internal teams and suppliers to rectify any issues, find solutions
April 2017 to June 2020 Company: Bagir Holdings UK Ltd. London, UK Job: Fabric Technologist	rand get approvals. Following customers' manual, implement various requirements and process throughout supply chain.
September 2010 to November 2016 Company: Alison Hayes UK Ltd. London, UK Job: Senior Fabric Technologist (joined initially as Junior fabric tech, then promoted)	Customers: ASOS, Boohoo, Ted Baker, Moss Bros, M&S, Next and various other brands. Suppliers: various mills in China, India, Turkey, Romania, Italy and Vietnam

June 2008 to August 2010	Responsibilities:
Company: Harvest Group Ltd, London, UK	Managing materials approvals, communicating
Job: Production co-ordinator	with customers and suppliers.
April 2007 to May 2008	Responsibilities:
Company: Rumana Money Services Ltd, London, UK	Data entry
Job: Administrative assistant	
July 2004 to February 2007	Responsibilities:
Company: Shanto-Mariam	Teaching students, Fashion and Textile Dpt
University of Creative Technology,	
Bangladesh Job: Lecturer	
December 1999 to March 2001	Responsibilities:
Company: MAICA Textilfabrik GmbH, Bangladesh	Quality checking and reporting
Job: Garment Technician (Quality Control)	
November 1997 to November 1999	
Company: Beximco Textiles Ltd, Gazipur,	Responsibilities:
Bangladesh	Creating recipe for lab dips, shade matching and
Job: Lab Officer	reporting

Education

M.Sc. in Textile and Clothing Engineering, Grade 2, Dresden University of technology, Germany, 2003 B.Sc. in Textile Technology, First Class, Dhaka University, Bangladesh, 1995 (exam held in 1997) Higher Secondary Certificate, First Division,

Subjects: Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, English (grade A to C), Dhaka Board, 1991

References available upon request